(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T10:11:00.086764",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アアア 愛 という 名 の 人体 実験 臨床
Ah, Ah, Ah, a human experiment and clinical trial named love
私は恋する C₈H₁₁NO₂
I'm falling in love with C₈H₁₁NO₂
カ カ カ 化学反応 心拍数の上昇 あなたに起こすの
Ka, Ka, Ka, chemical reaction, an increase in heart rate causing it inside you
生体反応“あいしている”
biological reaction: "I love you"
サ サ サ ササイケ フィーリング
Sa, Sa, Sa, psychedelic feeling
頭はガンガン 溢れて C₈H₁₁N
my head is throbbing, overflowing with C₈H₁₁N
ダ ダ ダ 大嫌い→から
Da, Da, Da, from "I hate you"
こんががって→陽性 その手を握れば
getting all tangled up -> positive, if you hold that hand
生体反応“あいしている”
biological reaction: "I love you"
理科室の鍵をかけたなら
If we lock the science room's door
私 天才だから 天才だから あなたの気持ちも分かっちゃう
Because I'm a genius, I can even figure out your feelings
あなたはだんだん 私を好きになる
You'll gradually come to like me
天才だから 天才だから あなたのすべてをも奪っちゃう
Because I'm a genius, I'll even steal away everything about you
脳神経→から 感覚細胞 意識の果てまで hack into
From cranial nerves to sensory cells, hack into the ends of consciousness
ナ ナ ナ 泣いて 泣いて は 脳内 環境 散々 求めて 足りない C₁₀H₁₂N₂O
Na, Na, Na, crying and crying makes the internal brain environment a mess, wanting and not having enough C₁₀H₁₂N₂O
バ バ バ バグのようだね 神経回路はおじゃん C₁₅₈H₂₅₁N₃₉O₄₆S で化かした幸福
Ba, Ba, Ba, it's like a bug, the neural circuits are fried, happiness faked with C₁₅₈H₂₅₁N₃₉O₄₆S
ラ ラ ラ ラブもライクも 中毒性の幻想 我らは恋する C₈H₁₁NO₂
Ra, Ra, Ra, both love and like are toxic illusions, we are in love with C₈H₁₁NO₂
ラ ラ ラ ラブもライクも 中毒性の幻想 愚かな病の生体反応
Ra, Ra, Ra, both love and like are toxic illusions, the biological reaction of a foolish illness
“あいしている” “あいしている”
"I love you", "I love you"
フラスコの中に落ちてゆく
Falling into the flask
私 天才だから 天才だから
I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
心の在り処も分かっちゃう
I even know where the heart resides.
あなたも私もお薬の言いなり
You and I are both slaves to medicine.
天才だから 天才だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
その先すべてが分かっちゃう
I understand everything beyond that.
水金地火木土天海 銀河の果てまで dive into
Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, dive to the edge of the galaxy!
嗚呼 愛も恋も化学式の中のマボロシ
Ah, both love and romance are illusions within chemical formulas.
私 天才だから 天才だから
I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
遠く全てが分かっちゃう
I understand everything far away.
そろそろこの世に飽きてきたころなの
It's about time I got tired of this world.
天才だから 天才だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
あなたのその手を掴んじゃう
I'll grab that hand of yours.
屋上階から飛び出して銀河の果てまで
Jump out from the rooftop, to the edge of the galaxy!
私 天才だから 天才だから
I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
鼓動の早さも分かっちゃう
I even know the speed of your heartbeat.
あなたはなんにも知らないお馬鹿さん
You're a fool who doesn't know anything at all.
天才だから 天才だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius.
愛など無くても分かっちゃう
I understand even without love.
脳神経→から感覚細胞 意識の果てまで全部埋めてよ
From cranial nerves to sensory cells, fill everything to the edge of consciousness!
ねぇ、あなたを“あいしてる”
Hey, I "love" you.
みんなー！今日は僕のお誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうーー！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
早速1曲目、「天才ロック」を歌わせていただきましたー！
We just performed the first song, "Tensai Rock"!
もうね、いっぱい激しく歌って踊ったので、もうだいぶヘトヘトなんですけど、まだまだね、値を上げるには早すぎるので、頑張っていきますよ！
Man, I sang and danced so fiercely that I'm pretty exhausted, but it's way too early to give up, so I'll keep doing my best!
そして今回は、いつもと……ん？いつもはちょっとやらないんですけど、みんながやってて僕もやってみたいなと思ったことがあったので、今回は実行してみました。
And this time, unlike usual... hm? I don't usually do this, but seeing everyone else do it made me want to try it too, so I tried it out this time.
今回僕のライブにタイトルを付けさせていただきましたーー！いぇーーい！どんぱふぱふーー！
I got to give a title to my live show this time! Yay! Woohoo!
え？そのままじゃんって？元々猫じゃんって？いいじゃん！タイトルつけてみたかったんだよ！
Eh? "Isn't that just as it is?" "Aren't you a cat to begin with?" It's fine! I just wanted to give it a title!
いつもは「猫又おかゆ生誕祭2022」とか「2021」とかだからさ、やってみたかったんだよ、ね？
Usually it's just "Nekomata Okayu Birthday Festival 2022" or "2021", so I wanted to try it, you know?
まあまあ、この日のためにいっぱい練習も準備もしてきたので、みんな瞬き現金で楽しんでいってね！
Well, I practiced and prepared a lot for this day, so everyone, enjoy it without even blinking!
それでは、まだまだライブ続きますので、引き続きお楽しみくださーい！
Well then, the live continues, so please continue to enjoy!
わっちゅーげっちょねっつれつもちゅー しゅきしゅきって弾けたvividマインド
Whatchu getcho, passionate mochi-chu, a vivid mind bursting with love!
ルーレットグッドスタートきってとけっといといといと
Roulette, good start, melting, thread by thread.
永久サンキューときめきKnock you 1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Eternal thank you, heart-pounding Knock you, diving into a 1mm gap.
ラブスタンプ全部コンプ 連勢アップ いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！せーの！
All love stamps complete, combo up, awesome! Ready, set!
だって今日はゴッドメンタル
Because today I've got god mental,
勇ましきチャレンジャー
A courageous challenger,
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental.
だいしきゅーだいしゅき♡いちにさんはい！
Super duper love you 1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめもめもめもまみれないの たちつてとてとてと手が触れて
Can't get enough of it, our hands touch.
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっと強制ラブ
Become super duper in love, more kyu-kyu, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート でもねこの胸見透かさないで
A clione's translucent heart, but don't see right through my chest.
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Become super duper in love, saying it's not me is so over.
わっちゅーげっちょみつげつもちゅー しゅきしゅきでからぶるCutieマインド
Whatchu getcho, secret honey-chu, a cutie mind spinning out from love.
ルーレットちょっとストップ一旦休憩 いや！いや！いや！でも！
Roulette, stop for a sec, quick break! No! No! No! But!
だって今日は求めてる
Because today I'm craving it,
勇ましきチャレンジャー
A courageous challenger,
ハート描いたオートメーション
An automated heart drawn,
だいしきゅーだいしゅき123はい！
Super duper love you 1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめもめろみし…
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo...
すき すき 大すき 超すき 超すき 超絶にすき
Love, love, big love, super love, super love, extremely in love!
好きって言ったら 想いが溢れて
When I say I love you, my feelings overflow,
なんだか なんだか 涙出そう
For some reason, I feel like crying...
勇気を出したら 想い伝わって
When I gather my courage, my feelings reach you,
今日から 今日から お付き合い
Starting today, starting today, we're going out!
Ah どうして こんなに好きなのよ
Ah, why do I love you this much?
あんまり言い過ぎるとウザがられちゃうわ
If I say it too much, you'll get annoyed with me,
でもね
But you know...
フレンドリーに アプリして 周波数を 見逃さないで
Be friendly, use the app, don't miss the frequency!
いわくつきの 魅惑のリップ リアルになる ミラー
An ill-fated, alluring lip becomes a real mirror.
まみむめももめも 見れないの
I can't even look!
立ちづってとてとてと手が触れて
Standing close, our hands brush against each other.
大すきー 大すきーになれ
Big love, grow into big love!
もっとキュッキュッキュッと強制ラブ！
More tightly, tightly, forced love!
あのねクリオネ 透けてるハート
You know, Clione, a translucent heart,
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But you know, don't see right through my chest!
大すきー 大すきーになれ
Big love, grow into big love!
あたしじゃないなんて
Saying it's not me...
終わってんねー！
Is so over!
まみむめももめももめも見れないの
I can't even look!
立ちづってとてとてとて手が触れて
Standing close, our hands brush against each other.
大すきー 大すきーになれ
Big love, grow into big love!
もっとキュッキュッキュッと強制ラブ！
More tightly, tightly, forced love!
あのねクリオネ 透けてるハート
You know, Clione, a translucent heart,
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But you know, don't see right through my chest!
大すきー 大すきーになれ
Big love, grow into big love!
あたしじゃないなんて
Saying it's not me...
終わってんねー！
Is so over!
ということで！ ということで！
And so! And so!
あの メス、バルトメカイユーで
Um, Me-Subaru and Me-Kayu!
メカイユー！？ メカブみたいになってる
Me-Kayu!? You sound like Mekabu!
なんでよ、メスバルトじゃないだろ別に！ メカブでもないだろお前は！
Why, I'm not Me-Subaru! And you're not Mekabu either!
まあまあまあ、ちょっとね、今回は可愛らしい曲をスバおかで歌わせていただきましたー！
Well, well, anyway, this time we got to sing a cute song as SubaOka!
いただきましたー！ おかゆお誕生日おめでとう！
We did! Happy birthday, Okayu!
ありがとう、スバルちゃん！
Thank you, Subaru-chan!
スバルちゃんとはね、事前に僕の誕生日にこの曲歌いたいから覚えといてねって言っといたんだよね。
Subaru-chan and I, I told her beforehand, "I want to sing this song on my birthday, so learn it okay?"
そう、で、ていうか、なんかマジでこの曲歌うみたいなことをね、聞いたときに
Yeah, and when I heard we were actually going to sing this song,
マジで震え上がったよの、マジで。
I was honestly shaking so hard, seriously.
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
いや、だ、大丈夫？みたいな。 いや、なんでこの曲に選んだの？
I was like, "Are you okay?" Why did you choose this song?
いや、やっぱり僕とスバルちゃんって、結構、戦友みたいな、そういうイメージあるじゃん？
Well, you know, Subaru-chan and I have sort of a comrades-in-arms kind of image, right?
まあね。
That's true.
そう。だから、今回は、ちょっと正統派ーてい、ていじゃないけど、そうゆうアイドるっぽい可愛いらしいスバおかをみんなにお届けしたいなって思ったんだよ。
Yeah. So this time, I wanted to deliver an idol-like, cute SubaOka that's a bit more orthodox... to everyone.
え、今までのって正統派ていじゃなかったの？ いや、ちょっとドロくさい
Eh, until now wasn't it orthodox? Well, a bit muddy—
ドロくさいとか言うな！ドロくさいて、だ、だってよ、いつもいい香りしてるだろ！
Don't call it muddy! Muddy—come on, you always smell so nice!
だから今日はすごくいい香りのしそうな感じで、お届けさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？
So today we delivered it with a feeling that seemed to smell really nice, how was it?
どうでした、皆さんも？スバルはね、もう、ずっと変な汗かきながらやってましたけどね。
How was it, everyone? Subaru was sweating weirdly the whole time doing it.
確かに、だいしゅーだいしゅき歌おうって言ったときに、スバルとおかゆでこの曲歌うの！？って言ってたもんね。
True, when you said let's sing Chouzetsu Suki, you were like, "Subaru and Okayu are singing this song!?"
だって！ もう、だいしゅーだいしゅきなんて、スバルのなかで一度も言ったことのない！
Because! I've never once in my life said "big, big love" as Subaru!
ね、言葉なんでにね。スバルちゃんがね、必死にね、脇汗かきながら覚えたから。
Right, those words. Subaru-chan was desperately learning it while sweating bullets.
脇汗書いてないわ！変なこと言うな！脇汗のおかげでね、こんなに… 脇汗じゃない！お前も脇汗かいてるだろ、じゃあ！
I wasn't sweating! Don't say weird things! It's not armpit sweat! You're sweating too then!
え、僕は書いてるよ。
Well, I am sweating.
キモい！気持ち悪いよ！
Gross! That's gross!
お誕生日お、お誕生日おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Happy b-happy birthday! Thank you!
じゃあ、もういいか？ もう、もう大丈夫、ありがとう。 大丈夫？ありがとうじゃなくて。
Well, is that good? Well, I'm okay now, thanks. Okay? Not thanks.
じゃあ、この後も頑張ってね！ はーい、ありがとう！
Well, do your best after this too! Okay, thank you!
はーい、バイバーイ！おめでとー！ はーい！
Bye-bye! Congrats! Bye!
にんじゃりばんばん
Ninja Re Bang Bang
鮮やかに 恋して にんじゃりばんばん なんだか にんじゃりばんばん bloom bloom bloom 花びらも舞う
Vividly falling in love, Ninja Re Bang Bang, bloom bloom bloom, flower petals dance.
飛んでけ にんじゃりばんばん 常識を変えたら 驚きが日常に
Fly away, Ninja Re Bang Bang, when you change common sense, surprises become everyday.
どうして にんじゃりばんばん 愛して にんじゃりばんばん Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Why, Ninja Re Bang Bang, loving, Ninja Re Bang Bang, Ring Ring Ring, a silent melody.
どうして にんじゃりばんばん
Why, ninja re bang bang?
愛して にんじゃりばんばん
Love me, ninja re bang bang!
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring, ring, ring, a silent melody,
ふんわり 煙に巻き
wrapped softly in smoke,
空を駆けるのは
running across the sky,
にんにんきん キミだけだから
nin-nin-kin, because it's only you!
見えていたものが七色に
What was visible turns into seven colors,
変わる時 キミはきっと
at that moment you surely
手をのばしても 触れない光のようだから
reach out your hand, but it's like an untouchable light.
きっと 手をのばしても
Even if you surely reach out your hand,
触れない光のようだから
it's like an untouchable light,
鮮やかに 恋して にんじゃりばんばん
Vividly falling in love, ninja re bang bang,
なんか こんじゃりばんばん
somehow, ninja re bang bang,
bloom bloom bloom 花びらも舞う
bloom bloom bloom, flower petals dance too,
飛んでけ にんじゃりばんばん
fly away, ninja re bang bang,
常識を変えたら 驚きが日常に
if you change common sense, surprise becomes everyday life.
どうして にんじゃりばんばん
Why, ninja re bang bang?
愛して にんじゃりばんばん
Love me, ninja re bang bang!
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring, ring, ring, a silent melody,
ふんわり 煙に巻き
wrapped softly in smoke,
空を駆けるのは
running across the sky,
にんにんきん キミだけだから
nin-nin-kin, because it's only you!
どんな色にもならないで
Without becoming any color,
キミは街を染めるよ
you dye the city,
広がっていくね
spreading out,
転がる巻物みたいな 道を作る
making a path like a rolling scroll,
鮮やかに 恋して にんじゃりばんばん
Vividly falling in love, ninja re bang bang,
なんか こんじゃりばんばん
somehow, ninja re bang bang,
bloom bloom bloom 花びらも舞う
bloom bloom bloom, flower petals dance too,
飛んでけ にんじゃりばんばん
fly away, ninja re bang bang,
常識を変えたら 驚きが日常に
if you change common sense, surprise becomes everyday life.
どうして にんじゃりばんばん
Why, ninja re bang bang?
愛して にんじゃりばんばん
Love me, ninja re bang bang!
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring, ring, ring, a silent melody,
ふんわり 煙に巻き
wrapped softly in smoke,
空を駆けるのは
running across the sky,
にんにんきん キミだけだから
nin-nin-kin, because it's only you!
鮮やかに 恋して にんじゃりばんばん
Vividly falling in love, ninja re bang bang,
なんか こんじゃりばんばん
somehow, ninja re bang bang,
bloom bloom bloom 花びらも舞う
bloom bloom bloom, flower petals dance too,
飛んでけ にんじゃりばんばん
fly away, ninja re bang bang,
常識を変えたら 驚きが日常に
if you change common sense, surprise becomes everyday life.
どうして にんじゃりばんばん
Why, ninja re bang bang?
愛して にんじゃりばんばん
Love me, ninja re bang bang!
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring, ring, ring, a silent melody,
ふんわり 煙に巻き
wrapped softly in smoke,
空を駆けるのは
running across the sky,
にんにんきん キミだけだから
nin-nin-kin, because it's only you!
色ハちゃん、にんにん！
Iroha-chan, nin-nin!
おかゆ先輩、ノートににんにん！レスジャキジャキでござるよ！
Okayu-senpai, nin-nin on your notes! That was super snappy, forsooth!
ごめんごめん。
My bad, my bad.
ということで、ホロックスの風間いろはちゃんが来てくれました！
And so, HoloX's Kazama Iroha-chan has come to join us!
どうもこんにちはでござる！
Hello there, forsooth!
改めまして、おかゆ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, Okayu-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
実は我々ね、裏でちょこちょこ遊んだりしてるんでござるよな。
Actually, you know, we hang out and play together behind the scenes sometimes.
そうなんですよ、実はね。まあ、仲良くさせてもらってます。
That's right, actually. Well, we get along really well.
僕がね、MIXとかに興味持ち始めたのも完全にいろはちゃんの影響というか、おかげなんですよね、いろはちゃん。
And me starting to get interested in mixing was completely due to Iroha-chan's influence!
うれしい！めちゃくちゃ嬉しいでござる！
I'm so happy! I'm so incredibly happy, forsooth!
いやいろはちゃんすごいさ、音源もさ……
Iroha-chan, you're amazing, your audio source...
え、おおかゆ先輩？おおかゆ先輩、ちょっと待って！
Eh, Okayu-senpai? Okayu-senpai, wait a second!
恥ずかしい恥ずかしい、ばらさないで！
That's embarrassing, don't give it away!
あ、ほんとに、もう、
Ah, really...
もう！
Oh!
嬉しいけど、えっちの音でござるよ、もう。
I'm so happy!
あ、ほんとに、もう、
Ah, a lewd sound!
えっちの音でござるよ、もう。
Aw, darn.
もう、どめかー。
Oh well.
でもね、今日は楽しかったです。
Yeah.
うん、残念だな。
Well, that's too bad.
で、でもね、今日は楽しかったです。
Yeah.
でもね、今日は楽しかったです。
Well, today was a lot of fun.
またぜひ一緒に遊びましょう！
Let's definitely play together again!
オッケー、ありがとう、いろはちゃん！
Okay, thank you, Iroha-chan!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
でござる〜！
Goodbye!
ゆれる街灯 しのつく雨
Trembling streetlights, pelting rain,
振れる感情 感覚のテレパス
trembling emotions, an emotional telepath.
迷子のふたりはコンタクト
The lost two made contact.
ココロは恋を知りました
My heart learned of love.
タイトロープ ツギハギの制服
A tightrope, a uniform of stitched-together pieces,
重度のディスコミュニケーション
a gravitational discommunication.
眼光 赤色にキラキラ
Glint, flashing red,
ナニカが起こる胸騒ぎ
something stirs an endless sense of dread.
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, yes, I'm an alien,
あなたの心を惑わせる
I'll lead your defenseless heart astray.
交ざり合う宇宙の引力で
Feeling this heartbeat in the milky way's gravity,
感じてる気持ちはトキメキ
it's thumping!
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, I'm your alien,
引き合う心は逃れられない
our intertwined hearts cannot escape.
あなたに未体験あげる
I'll show you an unworldly experience,
異世界の果てまで トキメキ スキ
to the edge of another dimension, thumping, love!
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
Fluorescent lights blinking on and off,
超大な混沌が 静かにあなたを蝕んだ
supernatural chaos quietly engulfs you.
並行な信号は 特異点に因り交わった
Parallel signals intersect at a singularity,
創造現実盲信症 感応性本能
a delusional reality blind spot, instinctive resonance.
シンドローム ひとりきり夜な夜な
A syndrome, alone every single night,
空想 描くまるですりもわは
a daydream sketched like a grimoire,
サーチライト 避ける浮遊機
a searchlight avoiding levitating craft.
「まだあなたは全てを知りたい?」
"Do you want to know everything about me yet?"
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, yes, I'm an alien,
あなたの心を惑わせる
I'll lead your defenseless heart astray.
瞳に映らない引力に気づいてよ わたしは
Notice the gravity unreflected in your eyes!
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, I'm your alien,
触れ合えば傷は二度と消えない
wounds won't ever fade if we touch.
降りそそぐ無数の隕石も
Countless falling meteors,
ときめく心には届かない!
still can't reach a thumping heart!
エイリアン ふたりはエイリアン
Alien, we are aliens,
高鳴る気持ちが抑えられない
this soaring feeling cannot be contained!
あなたは未確認生命体
Unidentified lifeform, you are,
異世界の果てまで あなたが好き
to the edge of another dimension, I love you!
おかゆ先輩！
Oka-yu Senpai,
おめでとう！
congrats!
おかゆ先輩！
Oka-yu Senpai,
おめでとう！
congrats!
おかゆ先輩？
Oka-yu Senpai?
そしそあい
Soshi-soai.
Soshi-soai!
おかゆ先輩！
Oka-yu Senpai,
おめでとう！
congrats!
おかゆ先輩！
Oka-yu Senpai,
誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
本日はお招きいただきまして、
Today, we were invited, so...
とても嬉しいかぎりです。
I'm so, so happy!
来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming.
私も一緒に歌えて嬉しかった。
I'm so happy we got to sing together too!
去年の9月のグラちゃんのライブの時もそうだったけど、
Just like Gura-chan's live back in September,
もうテンション上がりすぎて、ちゃんと歌えるか心配だったよー。
I was so nervous about whether I could sing properly because I was way too excited.
私もまたおかゆ先輩と一緒に歌えて、
I also got to sing with Oka-yu Senpai,
とっても嬉しかったです。
and it was so, so fun.
おかゆis soft and huggable,
Oka-yu is soft and huggable.
I'm sure everybody knows and wants to give Oka-yu a big hug.
Oka-yu is beautiful and soft and warm,
and... and... and...
Oka-yu... happiness!
なんか、とっても嬉しいことを言ってくれてる気がする！
Ah, I feel like you just said something super happy.
私もグラちゃんのこと大好きです！
I love Gura-chan so much too!
あ、あれ？
Ah, right?
お、おかゆ先輩？
O... Oka-yu Senpai?
おかゆ先輩？
Oka-yu Senpai?
Why are you looking at me like you're about to eat dinner?
あ、待って待って！触るだけだから。
Ah, wait, wait! I'm just touching you.
Really? 本当ですか？
Really? Is that true?
もぐもぐ
Nom, nom...
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
Don't be so rough. You have a tail, you should know how it feels.
ごめんごめん！ありがとう！おかげで元気が出たよ！ライブもまだまだ頑張れる！
My bad, my bad! Thank you! You gave me so much energy! I can keep giving it my all in the live!
今日は本当に来てくれてありがとう！また一緒に遊ぼうね！
Thank you so much for coming today! Let's hang out again together!
はーい！また一緒に歌いたいですね！
Yay! I'd love to sing together again!
ライブも頑張ってください！
Do your best on the live too!
ありがとう！バイバ～イ！バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
雨の季節が過ぎ 澄み渡る空を 眺めて独り想フ
Passing through the rainy season, I gaze at the clear sky, thinking alone.
きっと 君との距離はもう あの雲のように 遠くなってしまった
Surely, the distance between you and me has become as distant as those clouds.
思い出していた あの言葉 冬は良いけど夏は嫌
I remembered those words: "Winter is fine, but I hate summer."
愛しく想う程 彼女は苦しんだ そう僕も同じ
The more dearly I thought of her, the more she suffered—and so did I.
失う怖さと消えない気持ち まるで針鼠のジレンマ
The fear of loss and unfading feelings, like a hedgehog's dilemma.
朱の季節が過ぎ 澄み切った空は 冷たい風を運ぶ
As the scarlet season passes, the clear sky brings a cold wind.
ずっと 君との日々はもう 戻るはずもない そう諦めていた
I had given up, thinking our days together would never return.
戻って来たんだ 君は言う 寒い夜は 寄り添いたい
"I've come back," you say, wanting to snuggle on cold nights.
寂しく凍えそうな時には共に居た そう君と同じ 二度目の夏が近づいた
We were together only when freezing and lonely—just like you, a second summer is approaching.
このままでは過ちを繰り返すだけだろう
If things stay this way, we'll only repeat our mistakes.
いつまで続く 君との恋 煩わしくなる 君の体温
How long will this love with you last? Your body temperature becomes bothersome.
あなたの気持ち 分かってきたよ 冬だけの恋 熱い夜は寝苦しい
I've come to understand your feelings. A love only for winter makes hot nights restless.
寂しく凍えそうな時だけ共に居た そう君も同じ
We were together only when freezing and lonely—just like you.
今年も夏が近づいた このままでは過ちを繰り返すだけ
Summer has approached again this year. If things stay this way, we'll only repeat our mistakes.
愛しく想う程 彼女は苦しんだ そう僕も同じ
The more dearly I thought of her, the more she suffered—and so did I.
けれども いつか二人 裸で向き合える日が きっと来るはず
But surely the day will come when the two of us can face each other bare.
はい！1発目に続いてのソロ曲、「夏にさりし君を想フ」でしたー！
Yes! Following our first song, that was our solo song, "Thinking of You Who Left in Summer"!
この曲、僕めっちゃ好きで、みんなの前でいつか歌いたいなってずっとと思ってたの。ま、それが今日だったんだね。
I really love this song, and I've always wanted to sing it in front of everyone someday. Well, today was that day!
もう、ライブは中盤となっておりますが、引き続き楽しんでいただいてますか？僕らしいキャット様をまだまだ堪能していってね！
The live is already in the middle stretch, but are you still enjoying it? Please continue to fully enjoy the cat-sama that is uniquely me!
ちなみに、はっ……、すっ、すいません！あの、次のゲストはあの方です！
By the way, hah... ah, I'm sorry! Um, our next guest is that person!
らりぱっぱらぱっぱらっぱらりぱっぱらぱっぱらっぱ 純粋が仇になる世界で
Lalipappara... In a world where purity becomes a curse,
らりぱっぱらぱっぱらっぱらりぱっぱらぱっぱらっぱ また来週も戦えるかな
Lalipappara... I wonder if we can fight again next week.
可愛い衣装まとって 決めポーズで光って ピュアな想い魔法に変えて
Wearing cute outfits, shining in determined poses, changing pure feelings into magic,
みんなの平和願って 邪悪に立ち向かって それを匿名はディスった
Wishing for everyone's peace, standing up against evil, and anonyms dissed it.
本当は何なんでしょう？ぶっちゃけ何なんでしょう？
What on earth is it really? Honestly, what is it?
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness never ends well for me
また来週も戦えるかな
Can I have a break and finish fighting next week?
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
誰が敵か味方かわかんないし
Because friend or foe? How could I know? I'll never guess it
「陰険」で「強欲」で「滑稽」で「外道」で
"Devious", "the greediest", "ridiculous", "outrageous"
魔法がとける チョコみたいに
The worst kind of chocolate melts and taints my magic
ラリパッパラパッパラパッパラパ
Lali-pa-pala-pa-pala-pa
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness never ends well for me
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
もう好きな人だけ守っていたい
I only wanna keep my loved ones safe, honestly
だんだんと身勝手になる
Getting all the sel fisher
魔力が生え立つ
My magic runneth over
不満で調合したポーションがバリン！
The potion of dissatisfaction, up in smoke
性根が〇〇なんでしょ?
Deep down, you're xxx, aren't you?
怒りにまかせ 脳内で〇〇しちゃうでしょ?
You all make me so angry, in my head you're xxx, that's the truth
やり返しはナンセンス
I can't fight back, although I've tried
気に病んでてもスルーです
I've just learned to let it slide
光り失ったブローチ
The brooch's light fades fast like a popped fuse
腐る 腐る
Rotting, rotting
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
視聴者の期待に応えるたびに
Because every time I win the fight my audience says,
「完璧」で「超人」で「清廉」で「潔白」で
"You're perfect!" "Superhuman!" "So honest!" "So innocent!"
嘘で固めたチョコみたいに
The worst kind of chocolate wraps my lies like a gift
甘い味がやみつきでしょう
I can tell the taste is so addictive it stings
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
「やめないで」って言われいの期待してない?
Am I waiting for someone to tell me "Please, wait a bit!"
ファンの善意の〇〇も
The well-intentioned xxx, you
心配してる〇〇も
And the worried fans that xxx, too
すべて耳を塞いでしまったの
My cries fall on deaf ears, the pleading never made it through
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
誰が敵か味方かわかんないし
Because friend or foe? How could I know? I'll never guess it
「陰険」で「強欲」で「滑稽」で「外道」で
"Devious", "the greediest", "ridiculous", "outrageous"
魔法がとける チョコみたいに
The worst kind of chocolate melts and taints my magic
ラリパッパラパッパラパッパラパ
Lali-pa-pala-pa-pala-pa
魔法で最低な人を消そう
I'd erase them all if I could do it for free
はぁ 正直もうやめたい
Ah, honestly I wanna quit
魔法少女をやめたい
All the glitz makes me wanna quit
自分ごと消えちゃってさようなら
I'll erase myself instead, goodbye, the parting is sweet
ラリパッパラパッパラパッパラパ
Lali-pa-pala-pa-pala-pa
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness never ends well for me
また来週も観てくれるかな
I'll be back again, so finish watching next week!
はーい!どーも!おもたしなー!
Hi, everyone! Otonashi!
おたしなー!
Otonashi!
なんと2時3時さんからシナさんが僕のお祝いに来てくれました!
She came to celebrate my birthday from 2:00, 3:00 AM!
おー!
Oh!
特別やで ほんまに!
It's really special, truly!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you so much!
いや、おめでとうございます!
Yeah, congratulations!
いや、ありがとう!
Thank you!
ていうか、僕たち3Dでのらぶの初めてじゃない?
Come to think of it, this is the first time we've sung together in 3D, right?
よねー!
Yeah, right!
やばいよねー!
It's crazy, right?
ちょっとせっかくだから写真撮ってもらおうよ
Since it's a special occasion, let's take some photos!
うん!ね!
Yeah!
ピースピース!イェーイ!
Peace, peace! Yeah!
いやねこちゃんめっちゃいいな!
Man, Neko-chan is so cool!
え?ありがとー!
Eh? Thank you!
シナさんなら特別に触ってもいいよ
Since it's Shina-san, you can touch me specially.
あ、絵は!
Ah, eh? Wait!
おい!なんでだよ!
Hey, why'd you refuse?!
まあいいや、来月はね ちなみにかみおかラジオってあるんですかね?
Well whatever, next month is there a "Kamioka Radio" or something?
いや、どうやろなー!
Yeah, I wonder...
あ!
Ah!
もう時間よ!
It's time already!
え?
Eh?
うん、バイバーイ!おめでとう!
Yeah, bye-bye! Congratulations!
あ...
Ah...
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
A little sigh, every night
あなたの見てる正体
I keep on dreaming
誰も読めないカルテ
Don't you wish I knew how to show you why
不可思議 知りたいだけ
Call them lies or reality
嘘も現実も
It matters to me no more
どっちも事実だったの 本当よ
I'm sorry but, it's just the truth
今日もひとりごと
All i really ever wanted is to
なんにも無理をしないで わたし愛されたい
Be loved by someone who loves me
さよなら 軽い眩暈
You make me crazy
あなたのいない現象界
Won't you come back into my world tonight
誰も読めないカルテ 小さな溢れ出して
The remedy that is my fantasy
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
I can't talk, I can't sleep, Träumerei
いつも 噛み合わないの
We never seem to click,
いたくて
it hurts.
毎夜ねがいごと
Every night, I make a wish
なんにも疑わないで
without doubting a single thing.
混ざり溶け合いたい
I want to blend and melt into you.
たわいない 分からない 理由 存在
Trivial, unknown reasons and existence,
あなたと残す後悔
regrets left behind with you.
不愉快 繰り返して
Repeating unpleasantness over and over,
正しい夢は
A proper dream is...
かなしい声は
A sad voice is...
美しい？
Is it beautiful?
疑わしい？
Is it suspicious?
羨ましいね
Is it envious?
どれ？
Which one?
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
I can't talk, I can't sleep, Träumerei
あなたの見てる正体
The true form that you are seeing.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read.
不思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery.
終わらない ことはない トロイメライ
Nothing lasts forever, Träumerei,
あなたと跨ぐ境界
the boundary that I cross with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read.
思春期 傷口 胸のうち 不思議 知りたいだけ
Adolescence, a wound, deep in my heart—I just want to know the mystery.
ということで、ゲーマーズのみんなに集まってもらいました！
And so, I gathered everyone from Gamers here!
イエーイ！
Yay!
おかゆ、お誕生日おめでとうー！ありがとうー！
Happy birthday, Okayu! Thank you so much!
っていうかさ、今回のゲーマーズの曲、なんか全然ふざけてなくない？
But you know, this Gamers song... isn't it not silly at all?
え、思った！おかゆぴ、どういうことっすか？
Huh, I thought so too! Okayu-pi, what's that about?
えー、どういうこともこういうことも、たまにはゲーマーズもアイドルしてもいいんじゃないかなって思ってね。
Well, you know, sometimes it's fine for Gamers to act like idols too.
ほお、なるほど。うん。だから今年はアイドルしてもらわなくて大丈夫です。
I see, makes sense. Yeah, so this year you don't have to act like idols.
いやいやいやいや、え、そうなの？アイドルさせてよ！
No no no no, wait, really? Let us be idols!
大丈夫、大丈夫。1年に1回のノルマは達成してるんでね。
It's fine, it's fine. We've already met our once-a-year quota.
はー、確かに。ゲーマーズのノルマあったんだ？
Huh, true. Gamers had a quota?
そうでしょ？1年に1回やってる。ゲーマーズもね、もうちょっとさせようよ、手をと、ゲーマーズもね。
Right? We do it once a year. Gamers too, you know... let's do it a bit more, hand in hand, Gamers too.
ゲーマーズももう集まらなくて大丈夫だよ！
Gamers don't need to gather anymore either!
やりたいやりたい、わかったじゃねえよ！
We want to do it, we want to do it! "We don't need to"?!
え？はあ、そうだ！
Huh? Ah, that's right!
おかゆこうね、うちは、あの、うちはたちちょっと休業があってね。
Okayu and Korone, as for us... well, we had some time off.
ほら、生き込みを！行く行く、ふぶき、あ、ちゃちゃちゃ、バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Look, enthusiasm! Let's go, Fubuki—ah, cha cha cha, bye-bye! Bye-bye!
なんか、行っちゃったね。行っちゃったね。
Somehow, they left. They left.
これ、そろそろおがごろタイムかな？だね。
Is it about time for OgaGoro time? That's right.
すろおもおしょん ゆっくり変わってゆく
Slow motion, things are gradually changing.
コンビニで弁当買って部屋に帰って
Stopped by a convenience store to buy a bento box, went back to my room
テレビを見てた クイズの答え
and watched TV, knowing that the quiz answer
妥協と知って 夢と答える
was a compromise, answering with a dream.
ボケを続けて 熱が出ちゃって
Continuing to make jokes, getting a fever,
薬を飲んで 布団潜って目を閉じていた
taking some medicine, crawling under the futon and closing my eyes.
君のマネけない顔が浮かんできて
Your silly face popped into my head,
まだ死にたくないなんてのぼせながら
while getting dizzy thinking I don't want to die yet.
すろおもおしょん
Slow motion...
ゆっくり変わっていく
Slowly changing over time.
コンビニ寄って弁当買って
Stopped by the convenience store for bento,
部屋に戻ってテレビを見てた
went back to my room and watched TV.
クイズの答え妥協と知って
Knowing the quiz answer was a compromise,
夢と答えるボケを続けて
continuing to give dreamlike foolish answers.
熱が出ちゃって薬を飲んで
Running a fever, I took some medicine,
布団潜って目を閉じていた
crawled under the covers and closed my eyes.
君の間抜けな顔が浮かんで
Your goofy face popped into my mind,
まだ死にたくないなんてのぼせながら
while I was deliriously thinking, "I don't want to die yet."
十代 ドヤ顔で悟った人
Teens who figured it all out with a smug face,
二十代 恥に気づいた人
Twenties who realized their embarrassment,
三十代 身の丈を知った人
Thirties who learned their true limitations—
そのどれもが全部同じ人
every single one of them is the same person.
汗をかいて寝巻きを着替えたら
Sweating through my pajamas and changing them,
時計の針 午前零時
the clock hands point to midnight.
この曲は今 一分とちょっと
This song is now a minute and a bit long,
あなたは今 生まれて何年？
and how many years have you been alive?
すろおもおしょん 幼少から老年まで
Slow motion, from early childhood to old age,
こんでぃしょん 躁鬱の乱高下で
with wild swings of manic depression.
粘着でも不精でもない愛ひとつ届けたいのに
Wanting to deliver a single love that is neither clingy nor lazy,
こみゅにけえしょん 狙いすぎは滑って
communication where trying too hard falls flat,
おーでぃしょん 審美眼も老眼になって
audition where even aesthetic sense becomes presbyopic—
恥の多い生涯なんて珍しいもんじゃないし
a life full of shame is nothing rare,
大丈夫だよ
so it'll be fine.
好みによってパーツいじって
Tweaking parts according to taste,
愛を与えるビジネス知って
knowing the business of giving love,
過ぎた時間とこの瞬間と
the time that has passed and this moment,
残り時間が深夜混ざって
the remaining time mixed into the late night.
咳が酷くて水飲み干して
With a terrible cough, I drank all my water,
深呼吸してまた考えた
took a deep breath, and thought again.
鼻をすすって平和願い て
Sniffling and wishing for peace,
くしゃみしたら吹き飛ぶ諸行無常を
sneezing away the fleeting impermanence—
かつては無邪気に笑えた人
people who could once laugh innocently,
つまずいても涙こらえた人
people who held back tears even when stumbling,
どんどんくたびれた顔の人
people whose faces grew increasingly weary,
そしてしわの増えた同じ 人
and the same people with increased wrinkles.
ぬるくなった冷えピタを取り替えて
Replacing the lukewarm cooling sheet,
時間はまだ丑三つ時
the time is still the dead of night.
この曲は残り二分とちょっと
This song has two minutes and a bit left,
あなたの寿命はあと何年？
and how many years of life do you have left?
ぐらでゅええしょん 入学から卒業 まで
Graduation, from enrollment to graduation,
ぱあてぃしょん 水面下で喧嘩し て
partition, fighting beneath the water's surface.
忘れちゃいけないこと以外はどうでもよくなりゃいいのに
Wishing everything except what shouldn't be forgotten didn't matter,
いまじねえしょん 刺激で変化し ちゃっ て
imagination, changed by stimulation,
れりじょん 盲目な先入観で
religion, with blind preconceptions.
変顔のイカス遺影だってあざといとつつか れる
Even a cool memorial photo making a funny face gets poked at for being manipulative—
そんなもんだよ
that's just how it is.
のりりくらり のたうちまわり
Rolling and writhing around lazily,
じわりじわり 見覚えのない場所 に
slowly drifting into an unfamiliar place.
感傷感傷に身をやつしても
Even if I give myself over to sentimentality,
へっくしょんへっくしょん くしゃみは馬鹿っぽい な
"Achoo, achoo," sneezing sounds so silly.
ぐーすぴーぐーすぴー 鼻づまりの笛 を
"Zzz... zzz..." blowing a stuffy nose flute,
合図に夜が明けてく
as a signal that dawn is breaking.
すろおもおしょん 朝になって熱引いて
Slow motion, morning comes and the fever subsides,
こんでぃしょん 快晴の青天井で
condition, under a clear blue sky.
反省したり調子こいたりのんびりくたばっていく
Reflecting, getting cocky, and leisurely passing away.
すろおもおしょん アイドルだって年くっ て
Slow motion, even idols grow old,
わいどしょん 賑わって骨になって
wide show, bustling until turning to bones.
生まれた時と最後の時がゆっくり繋がる不思議
The wonder of birth and the final moment slowly connecting—
こんびねえしょん 良い人に出会うため
combination, to meet a good person,
くえすちょん 良い人ってどんなん かね？
question, what is a "good person" even like?
恥の多い生涯なんて
A life full of shame...
どんがらがつちゃん それそれ
crashing and banging, yeah!
すっからかんの ほれほれ
completely empty, look, look!
珍しいもんじゃないし
It's nothing rare,
大丈夫だよ
so it'll be fine.
すろおもおしょん
Slow motion...
ゆっくり終わっていく
slowly coming to an end.
すろおもおしょん
Slow motion...
ゆっくり変わっていく
Slowly changing over time.
コンビニ寄って弁当買って
Stopped by the convenience store for bento,
部屋に戻ってテレビを見てた
went back to my room and watched TV.
クイズの答え妥協と知って
Knowing the quiz answer was a compromise,
夢と答えるボケを続けて
continuing to give dreamlike foolish answers.
熱が出ちゃって薬を飲ん で
Running a fever, I took some medicine,
布団潜って目を閉じていた
crawled under the covers and closed my eyes.
君の間抜けな顔が浮かんで
Your goofy face popped into my mind,
まだ死にたくないなんてのぼせながら
while I was deliriously thinking, "I don't want to die yet."
十代 ドヤ顔で悟った人
Teens who figured it all out with a smug face,
二十代 恥に気づいた人
Twenties who realized their embarrassment,
三十代 身の丈を知った人
Thirties who learned their true limitations—
そのどれもが全部同じ人
every single one of them is the same person.
汗をかいて寝巻きを着替えたら
Sweating through my pajamas and changing them,
時計の針 午前零時
the clock hands point to midnight.
この曲は今 一分とちょっと
This song is now a minute and a bit long,
あなたは今 生まれて何年？
and how many years have you been alive?
すろおもおしょん 幼少から老年まで
Slow motion, from early childhood to old age,
こんでぃしょん 躁鬱の乱高下で
with wild swings of manic depression.
粘着でも不精でもない愛ひとつ届けたいのに
Wanting to deliver a single love that is neither clingy nor lazy,
こみゅにけえしょん 狙いすぎは滑って
communication where trying too hard falls flat,
おーでぃしょん 審美眼も老眼になって
audition where even aesthetic sense becomes presbyopic—
恥の多い生涯なんて珍しいもんじゃないし
a life full of shame is nothing rare,
大丈夫だよ
so it'll be fine.
好みによってパーツいじっ て
Tweaking parts according to taste,
愛を与えるビジネス知って
knowing the business of giving love,
過ぎた時間とこの瞬間 と
the time that has passed and this moment,
残り時間が深夜混ざって
the remaining time mixed into the late night.
咳が酷くて水飲み干して
With a terrible cough, I drank all my water,
深呼吸してまた考えた
took a deep breath, and thought again.
鼻をすすって平和願い て
Sniffling and wishing for peace,
くしゃみしたら吹き飛ばす諸行無常を
sneezing away the fleeting impermanence—
かつては無邪気に笑えた人
people who could once laugh innocently,
つまずいても涙こらえた人
people who held back tears even when stumbling,
どんどんくたびれた顔の人
people whose faces grew increasingly weary,
そしてしわの増えた同じ人
and the same people with increased wrinkles.
ぬるくなった冷えピタを取り替え て
Replacing the lukewarm cooling sheet,
時間はまだ丑三つ時
the time is still the dead of night.
この曲は残り二分とちょっと
This song has two minutes and a bit left,
あなたの寿命はあと何年？
and how many years of life do you have left?
ぐらでゅええしょん 入学から卒業まで
Graduation, from enrollment to graduation,
ぱあてぃしょん 水面下で喧嘩して
partition, fighting beneath the water's surface.
忘れ ちゃ いけないこと以外はどうでもよくなりゃいいのに
Wishing everything except what shouldn't be forgotten didn't matter,
いまじねえしょん 刺激で変化し ちゃっ て
imagination, changed by stimulation,
れりじょん 盲目な先入観で
religion, with blind preconceptions.
変顔のイカス遺影だってあざといとつつか れる
Even a cool memorial photo making a funny face gets poked at for being manipulative—
そんなもんだよ
that's just how it is.
のりりくらり のたうちまわり
Rolling and writhing around lazily,
じわりじわり 見覚えのない場所に
slowly drifting into an unfamiliar place.
感傷感傷に身をやつしても
Even if I give myself over to sentimentality,
へっくしょんへっくしょん くしゃみは馬鹿っぽい な
"Achoo, achoo," sneezing sounds so silly.
ぐーすぴーぐーすぴー 鼻づまりの笛を
"Zzz... zzz..." blowing a stuffy nose flute,
合図に夜が明けてく
as a signal that dawn is breaking.
すろおもおしょん 朝になって熱引い て
Slow motion, morning comes and the fever subsides,
こんでぃしょん 快晴の青天井で
condition, under a clear blue sky.
反省したり調子こいたりのんびりくたばっていく
Reflecting, getting cocky, and leisurely passing away.
すろおもおしょん アイドルだって年くっ て
Slow motion, even idols grow old,
わいどしょん 賑わって骨になって
wide show, bustling until turning to bones.
生まれた時と最後の時がゆっくり繋がる不思議
The wonder of birth and the final moment slowly connecting—
こんびねえしょん 良い人に出会うため
combination, to meet a good person,
くえすちょん 良い人ってどんなんかね？
question, what is a "good person" even like?
恥の多い生涯なんてどんがらが得っちゃんなんて
A life full of shame, crashing and banging...
すっからかんのほれほれ珍しいもんじゃないし
completely empty, look, look, it's nothing rare,
大丈夫だよ
so it'll be fine.
すろおもおしょん すろおもおしょん
Slow motion, slow motion...
ああ ゆっくり終わっていく
Ah, slowly coming to an end.
すろおもおしょん
Slow motion...
あらためておかゆ お誕生日おめでとう！
Once again, Happy Birthday, Okayu!
せーの、ありがとう！
Ready, set—thank you!
やっぱりふたりの時間もほしいなって思って
I thought it'd be nice to have some time for just the two of us too.
「来年も」って、そんなこと思ってて…あっ、戻ってきた！
I was thinking, "Next year too..." Oh, we're back!
ちょっとゆっくり、ゆっくりおしゃべりで、お送りしましたけど
We delivered this with a bit of a slow, relaxed chat,
はい、今回は「スロースモーション」っていう曲にふたりで挑戦してみました！楽しかった！
yeah, this time the two of us tried covering the song "Slow Motion"! That was fun!
ぬーん、この曲すっごく元気になれるよね。
Nrn, this song really gets your energy up, doesn't it?
わかーる！これでもね、この日に向けてね、いっぱい聞き込んできたからね、すごい今ね、ジーンとしてるよ、おがゆ。
I know, right! I've been listening to this so much leading up to today, so I'm really feeling touched right now, Okayu.
よかった。
I'm glad.
嬉しい、楽しい、大好き！
Happy, fun, I love it!
ぼくも大好きだよ。
I love it too.
わぁ！いつかね、絶対二人で歌ってみたいなって思ってたんだよね。
Wah! I've always wanted us to sing together someday.
え、嬉しい！
Eh, I'm so happy!
ていうかぼく、いつも自分のライブで好きな歌をころさんにも歌ってもらえるっていうのが、すごい嬉しいんだよ。
And you know, I'm always so happy that whenever I have my live, Korosan sings my favorite songs.
え、ちょっと言わせてもらっていい？
Eh, can I say something?
おがゆがさ、自分のさ、好きな曲をさ、歌いたいって言ってくれるのがさ、嬉しいんだよね。
It makes me so happy when Okayu says she wants to sing her favorite songs.
じゃあやっぱり来年もまたころさんと一緒にいろいろ歌っていきたいね。
Then I definitely want to keep singing various things with Korosan next year too.
イエーイ！
Yay!
待ってまーす！じゃあソロえなくなったら、ちょっとアツかけますので。
We'll be waiting! So once solo is gone, I'll put on some pressure.
あ、分かりました。
Ah, understood.
じゃあソロえなくなったらそういうことで。
Then once solo is gone, that's how it'll be.
長い、やめろ！
Too long, stop it!
じゃあせっかくね、おがころ揃ってるんで、今日もちょっと一緒にピースとかしてね、みんなにスクショ撮ってもらおう。
Since Okatone are both here, let's do peace signs together today and have everyone take screenshots.
スクショタイムしよう、スクショタイム！
Let's do screenshot time, screenshot time!
せーの！
Ready, set!
ピース！いぇーい！
Peace! Yay!
撮れてる？可愛く撮ってね。
Did you get it? Take cute ones.
可愛く撮ってよー！
Take cute ones!
あじゃあ、もう一枚ぐらい撮っときたいね。
Ah then, I want to take about one more.
ポーズだ二種か
Two kinds of poses?
ポーズはね、うーん、うわっ！
Poses are, hmm, woah!
ころさん！
Korosan!
待って！
Wait!
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
あ、風が来る！
Ah, wind is coming!
ころさんのところだけに突風が吹く！
A gust of wind is blowing only at Korosan's place!
ころさん！ころさん！ころさん！
Korosan! Korosan! Korosan!
ころさん、いっちゃったね。
Korosan... she's gone.
あ、スタッフさん、ちょっとお水もらってもいいですか？あ、ありがとうございます。
Ah, staff-san, could I get some water? Ah, thank you very much.
なんか、いつも飲んでる水とはちょっと違う味がするな。
Somehow, this tastes a bit different from the water I usually drink.
はあー！て、展開としてはだいぶベタだけど、なんか体が光ってて……へん！や、やあー！
Haaah! Th-the development is pretty cliché, but somehow my body is glowing... Weird! Ya, yaaah!
おーけーおーけー ぼくが君の 神様になったげる
Okay! Okay! I'll become your god!
（お願ーい！お願ーい！）
(Please! Please!)
しょうがないなー
Can't be helped~
（お願ーい！お願ーい！たすけておかゆーん！）
(Please! Please! Help me, Okayu-un!)
やぁやぁ、悩める現代の皆様
Hey hey, troubled folks of modern times,
けたたましい時代の只中
Right in the middle of a noisy era,
自分の事さえ 愛せない
Unable to even love yourself—
そんなこと ありませんか？
Isn't there something like that?
「誰かに認めてもらいたいな…」
"I want someone to acknowledge me..."
「何も上手くいかずヤダヤダ」
"Nothing goes well, no no no"
神頼み それなのに
Praying to gods, yet—
どこに行ったら会えるの神様
Where do I go to meet a god?
（Help me！）どうしたの〜？
(Help me!) What's wrong~?
（Help me！）うんうん
(Help me!) Uh-huh.
（Help me！）そっか、大変だね〜
(Help me!) I see, that's tough~
（Save me！）でもね〜
(Save me!) But you know~
（Save me！）大丈夫！
(Save me!) It's okay!
ぼくが味方でいるからさっ
Because I'm on your side!
生きてるだけで満点（満点！）
Just living is a full score (Full score!)
自信持ちなよ全然（全然！）
Have confidence, absolutely (Absolutely!)
信じていいよ当然（当然！）
You can believe it, naturally (Naturally!)
君はとっても素敵だよ！
You are so wonderful!
ありとあらゆる この世の全てを
Affirming everything in this world—
肯定！肯定！
Affirm! Affirm!
全知全能全肯定！
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
「それって結構、神じゃない？」
"Isn't that pretty much being a god?"
いい じゃん！いい じゃん！すごい じゃん！（すごーい！）
Good! Good! Amazing! (Amazing!)
いい じゃん！いい じゃん！えらい じゃん！（えらーい！）
Good! Good! Great! (Great!)
そう です そう です もっと 自由に 生きて いいんだよ 全肯定
That's right, that's right, live more freely, total affirmation!
いい じゃん！いい じゃん！すごい じゃん！（すごーい！）
Good! Good! Amazing! (Amazing!)
いい じゃん！いい じゃん！えらい じゃん！（えらーい！）
Good! Good! Great! (Great!)
おーけーおーけー 君は最高 何度だって伝え上げる
Okay! Okay! You're the best, I'll tell you however many times it takes!
（お願ーい！お願ーい！）
(Please! Please!)
しょうがないなー
Can't be helped~
（お願ーい！お願ーい！たすけておかゆーん！）
(Please! Please! Help me, Okayu-un!)
承認欲求 マウント社会 マイナス思考に自己否定
Need for approval, status-driven society, negative thinking and self-denial,
誰かがみんな求め続ける
Everyone keeps searching for...
自分だけにある特別感
A sense of uniqueness that only belongs to them.
数値化されちゃう世知辛時代 いいね フォロワー 高評価
A harsh era where everything is quantified: likes, followers, high ratings.
そんなの全然必要ないよ ぼくの言葉に全て委ねて
You don't need any of that at all. Entrust everything to my words.
あーね！いいじゃん！うんうん！えらーい！
Ah-ha! Good! Uh-huh! Great!
おー！かんぺき！今日もおつかれ！
Oh! Perfect! Good job today too!
グッド！けっこう！こうてい！こうてい！さすが自信持って！
Good! Pretty good! Affirm! Affirm! As expected, have confidence!
すばらしい！せかいいち！そばにいるよ！
Wonderful! Best in the world! I'm by your side!
だいすき！ちょうすき！つまりすき！
I love you! Super love you! In short, I love you!
できるよ！とうぜん！なんとかなるよ！にっこり！ぬくぬくねこかわいがり！
You can do it! Naturally! It'll work out! Smile! Warm, doted-on cat love!
神様も 人様も なにものも 信じられなくても 猫様を 信じましょう
Even if you can't believe in gods, people, or anything else, let's believe in Neko-sama.
甘えましょう 与えましょう 安心 晴れの日も 雨の日も
Let's indulge, let's give, peace of mind. On sunny days and rainy days alike,
支えましょう 君の心を 病む時 泣ける時 ここに来たならもう大丈夫
Let's support your heart. When you're sick, when you want to cry, if you come here, you'll be okay.
（Help me！）はいはい
(Help me!) Yes, yes.
（Help me！）よしよし
(Help me!) There, there.
（Help me！）うんうん、心配しないで （Save me！）ほらね （Save me！）大丈夫！
(Help me!) Uh-huh, don't worry. (Save me!) See? (Save me!) It's okay!
君もレッツおにぎりゃー！
You too, let's Onigiriya!
いい じゃん！いい じゃん！すごい じゃん！
Good! Good! Amazing!
ほらね、
See?
大丈夫ね。
It'll be alright.
君もレッツ おにぎりゃー！
You too, let's Onigiryaa!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
That's great, that's wonderful!
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
That's good, that's amazing!
そうです そうです もっとぼくの側に置いてよ 全肯定
That's right, keep me closer by your side, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
That's great, that's wonderful!
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
That's good, that's amazing!
オーケー オーケー ぼくさ君の 猫様になれたげる
Okay, okay, I'll become your cat god!
のんびりいこうよ ばっちりピカイチ ファンタスティック
Let's take it easy, perfectly top-notch, fantastic!
へっちゃらポジティブ まあまあ みんな無理しないでね
No worries, positive, hey now, everyone don't push yourselves!
めっちゃ心配だよ もぐもぐ やっぱり 勇気のよっしゃいくぞ！
I'm super worried! Munch munch... as expected, courage, here we go!
肯定 肯定 肯定 肯定 全知全能 全肯定！
Affirmation, affirmation, affirmation, affirmation, omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
さぁさぁ皆さん ご唱和ください！
Come on everyone, please chant along!
全知全能 全肯定！
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん
That's great, that's wonderful!
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
That's good, that's amazing!
オーケー オーケー 新世界の神様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become the god of a new world!
らくにいこうよ
Let's take it easy
りょーこーるーむ
Travel room
レッツゴーろーろー
Let's go ro-ro
笑ってこー
Let's smile
わあ なんか神様になっちゃったよ
Whoa... somehow I became a god.
ということで 皆さん改めてまして 今年も私の生誕祭に来てくれてありがとうございました！
So everyone, once again, thank you so much for coming to my birthday stream!
皆様の応援のおかげで いつも楽しく活動できています 月並みな言葉にはなるんですが 本当に感謝してます！
Thanks to your support, I'm always having fun streaming. It's a cliché, but I'm truly grateful!
今年も好きなこといっぱいやって うおーって頑張りたいと思いまーす！
This year too, I want to do lots of things I love and work hard with a big 'Woo'!
おにぎりゃ 大好き ちゅっ
Onigiryaa, I love you, muah!
えーっと あとなんか言わないといけないことがあったような なかったような 最近物忘れが激しくて困るな
Umm, also, it feels like there was something I had to say, or maybe not. Lately my forgetfulness is terrible.
あ そうだそうだ あのね このあと猫又おかゆチャンネルにて 神様猫様のMVがこのあとすぐ公開されます
Ah, that's right! Um, after this, on the Nekomata Okayu channel, the MV for 'Kamisama Nekosama' will be released right after!
もう動画すっごいから みんなに絶対見てほしい！ 頼むよ この動画をみんなに見せられるのすっごい楽しみにしてたんだから！
The video is amazing, so I definitely want everyone to watch it! Please! I was looking forward so much to showing this video to everyone!
あ あと グッズの告知もこのあとすぐあるので まだ帰らないでください！
Ah, also, merchandise announcements are coming right after this too, so don't leave yet!
もぐもぐおかゆ ライブ見てくれてありがと！ すっごく楽しかった！
Mogu Mogu Okayu! Thanks for watching the live! It was super fun!
ここからは2023年のぼくのグッズの告知になるよ！いぇーい！
From here on is the announcement for my 2023 merchandise! Yay!
今年のグッズはお風呂に入るときや出かけるときに使える感じにしてみました！ボイスももりだくさんです！たくさん考えて作ったので気合いを入れて詳しく紹介していくぞ！
This year's merchandise is designed for baths and outings! Lots of voices too! I thought a lot about it, so I'll introduce it in detail!
まず どーん！お風呂ポスター！ずっと出してみたかったんだよね！イラストは今年も神岡ちろるママの描き下ろしです！とってもかわいい！
First, boom! Bath poster! I've always wanted to release one! The illustration is newly drawn by Kamioka Chirol-mama! So cute!
これでお風呂に入るときもずっと一緒だよ！おにぎりゃ 早くお風呂一緒にいこー！
This way we'll be together even in the bath! Onigiryaa, let's hurry and take a bath together!
続いてはこちら！初めてのランダムアクリルキーホルダーです！イラストはなもり先生の描き下ろしです！ミニマムな感じでかわちすぎる！
Next is this! The first random acrylic keychain! The illustration is newly drawn by Namori-sensei! It's so minimalist and ultra-cute!
ぼく自身がランダム系のグッズってワクワクするからめっっちゃ大好きで 今回出してみました！通常衣装 制服衣装 シャツ衣装 ポイズン衣装の全4種類となっています！どの僕が当たっても大事にしてほしいな！
I personally get super excited about random merchandise, so I love it and released it! There are 4 types in total! Whichever 'me' you get, I hope you treasure it!
続いては こちら！おにぎりゃデザインのポロシャツ！全体ライブのときとか おにぎりゃがたくさん集まるときにぜひ着てほしいなと思ってデザインしてみました！もちろん普段使いもしやすいかなと思います！
Next is this! The Onigiryaa-designed polo shirt! I designed this thinking I'd want you to wear it when lots of Onigiryaa gather! Of course, it's also easy for everyday wear!
襟が黒くてシックにしてるのがおしゃれなポイントです！ぜひ着てみてね！デートに行くときはこの服で来てほしいな！
The chic black collar is a stylish point! Please try wearing it! When going on a date, I'd want you to come in this outfit!
そしてつづきまして こちら！ハンドタオル！こちらポロシャツとお揃いの刺繍が入っております！気楽に身につけられるものもいいかなと思ってタオルも出してみました！
And continuing with this! Hand towel! This has the same embroidery as the polo shirt! I thought something easy to wear/use would be nice, so I also released a towel!
いっぱいこれで おててをふきふきしていきましょう！
Let's wipe our hands clean with this lots!
フキフキ！
Wipe wipe!
そして最後、ボイスを今回はドドドンと取り下ろしました！
And finally, we recorded brand new voice packs this time!
グッズを身につけながら聞くと、ぐっと臨場感が出て、よりドキドキできちゃう内容もあります。
If you listen while wearing the goods, it adds immersion and some parts will make your heart race even more.
全部紹介すると、もう無限に説明しちゃうので、ぎゅっとまとめてお話しするね。
If I introduced all of them, I'd explain endlessly, so I'll summarize it for you.
まず、激甘いち押しボイス！お布団で密着添い寝ボイス。
First, the super sweet top-recommendation voice! The close-contact cuddling in bed voice.
運営さんに相談しながら、ラインギリギリを攻めてみました。
Consulting with management, I pushed it right to the limit.
バイノーラル音声なので、ぜひヘッドホンやイヤホンで堪能してみてください。
It's binaural audio, so please enjoy it with headphones or earphones.
次、お風呂上がりに膝枕されながら耳かきボイス！
Next, the post-bath lap pillow ear-cleaning voice!
こちらもバイノーラルマイクで収録しました。耳かき音もごりごり気持ち良くなっちゃったね。
This was also recorded with a binaural mic. The ear-cleaning sounds became super satisfying too.
そして最後、シチュエーションボイス3点。
And finally, 3 situation voices.
こちらはグッズを身につけながら聞くと、いっぱい楽しめるかなって内容になってます。全部甘々です。
These are contents you can enjoy a lot more while wearing the goods. They're all super sweet.
キーホルダーに嫉妬するボイスは、個人的にちょっと恥ずかしい。ううん、何でもない、何でもない、何でもないよ。
The voice of jealousy towards the keychain is a bit embarrassing personally. No, nothing at all, nothing at all!
そしてそして、こちらのグッズを全部買ってくれた人には、
And then, for everyone who bought all these goods,
僕の直筆サイン入りポストカードが一緒につれてくるよ！イエーイ！
my handwritten autographed postcard will come with it! Yay!
一生懸命、丹精込めて書かせていただきます。
I'll write each one with all my heart and care.
あ、ちなみに無制限となってます。お任せあれ！
Oh, by the way, it's unlimited. Leave it to me!
はあ、いっぱい喋ったあ。
Phew, I talked a lot.
詳しくはオフィシャルサイトにも詳細書いてあるので、ぜひ見てみてね。
For details, check out the official site as well, so please take a look.
また今年もたくさん配信してくから、改めてよろしくお願いします！
Also I'll stream a lot this year too, so I look forward to your continued support!
いくよ！感触、おかゆ、バイバーイ、んまっ！
Here we go! Feel... Okayu, bye-bye, mwah!
I’m a swinging cat, Kick Snare Hihat
Groovy growl ほら騒々しい音が鳴るよ
Groovy growl, look, noisy sounds are ringing out
I got to be free, Take it easy 今日もぐんぐん育む心身
I got to be free, Take it easy, growing body and mind today too
食べる寝る遊ぶ繰り返しピンピン You know?
Eating, sleeping, playing, on repeat, feeling great, you know?
気軽にやってくるピンチ だから用意する本気スイッチ
Pinches come easily, so I prepare my serious switch
だってこの世はヘルズキッチン You know?
Because this world is Hell's Kitchen, you know?
迫り来る自堕落 怠惰の魔の手に対抗する欲望自制自制
Resisting the closing hands of self-indulgence and laziness, desire, self-control
でもそれ生きている意味あるの？って疑問から生まれるメッセージ性
But is there any meaning to living like that? A message born from that question
いつでもやる気じゃんさいだし、いつでも怠けちゃ虚しいし、
Always being motivated is tiresome, always being lazy is empty,
いつでも悩みは鬱陶しいからお気楽に Do that shit (Sounds good!)
and always worrying is annoying, so carefree, do that shit (Sounds good!)
両の目で獲物を見定めてる 心の奥くすぐる香り
Spotting the prey with both eyes, the scent tickling deep in my heart
満ちた月のように丸めてる モノクロに咲く鮮やかなハーモニー
Rounded like a full moon, a vivid harmony blooming in monochrome
Grrr Grrr Tummy, Ready steady go!
ぐずぐずお腹が Skrr Skrr (Bravo)
Rumbling tummy goes Skrr Skrr (Bravo)
Grrr Grrr Tummy, Ready steady go!
超超自由でいたいから強食自愛 (Aiight)
Wanting to be super-duper free, so survival of the fittest self-love (Aiight)
Good good good good timing, dig in
ぎゅーぎゅーに詰まってる愛 粒々辛味忘れられない
Love packed tightly, grain by grain, unforgettable spice
Let me see...
Mogu Mogu Yummy, Meow Meow Kitty
Zzz Zzz Sleepy, Grrr Grrr Tummy
マイライフ順風満帆 だってお腹もパンパン
My life is smooth sailing, because my belly is full too
狙ってる虎視眈々 毎夜まんまるの晩餐
Eyeing it like a tiger, every night a round banquet
如何なる時でも感応すれば お目目ハートマークのマンチカン
No matter when, if I sense it, a Munchkin with heart-shaped eyes
コンプかかったお米のジャンキー You know, you know?
A rice junkie with completed sets, you know, you know?
小腹が空いたらキャッチ 昼夜問わずおやつは3時
Catch me when I'm slightly hungry, day or night snack time is 3
ディナー ブレークファースト ランチ ブランチ You know, you know?
Dinner, breakfast, lunch, brunch, you know, you know?
無芸大食なんて言わせない 好きが高じて今やゲーマー
Don't call me a glutton with no other skills, love grew so much I'm a gamer now
だって「すげー」「最高」とか言わせたい しっかり上げるパラメータ
Because I want them to say "awesome" or "the best", raising my parameters steadily
いつでもブレずに従うし いつでも変わらない自分自身
Always following without wavering, always my unchanging self
いつでも欲しがっちゃう「おいしー」 また一垂らし (Sounds grrr...)
Always craving "delicious", once more drizzled (Sounds grrr...)
思考の余裕与えず丸め込む 腹黒いアンフェアなノリはno!
Rolling them up without giving room for thought, dark and unfair vibes are no!
そんなのより愛情で包み込む 選びすぐり各自の好み内包
Wrap them in love instead, embracing everyone's curated preferences
Grrr Grrr Tummy, Ready steady go!
ぐずぐずお腹が Skrr Skrr (Bravo)
Rumbling tummy goes Skrr Skrr (Bravo)
Grrr Grrr Tummy, Ready steady go!
超超自由でいたいから強食自愛 (Aiight)
Wanting to be super-duper free, so survival of the fittest self-love (Aiight)